Recall that I'm referring to the first stock as butter pecan ice cream.
之前我将第一支股票看作奶油胡桃冰激凌
The second stock can be modeled in a similar way.
第二支股票也可以按照类似的方式建模
We can think of it as another flavor of ice cream.
我们可以将其看作另一种口味的冰激凌
Like mint chocolate chip.
例如薄荷巧克力碎
Similar to before, the second stocks variance can be modeled as two parts.
和之前差不多 第二支股票的方差可以由两部分组成
The part that is explained by the common risk factors,
一个是公共风险因子能解释的部分
and the part that is not.
另一个是公共因子无法解释的部分
I'd like to point out something very cool.
比较有趣的是
Which is that all the values that you see inside a variance operator or
方差和协方差运算符中的所有值
covariance operator contain just the risk factor as one in two.
都只包含风险因子 1 和 2
Which we've nicknamed sugar and milk.
我们称其为糖和牛奶
The variance and covariance functions don't need
方差和协方差函数
to include information that is specific to
不需要包含
the stocks because we can take
特定于股票的信息
the factor exposures outside of the variance and covariance operators.
因为我们可以从方差和协方差运算符中拿出因子暴露度
This is very helpful because as you'll see later on,
这很有用 后面你会发现
it greatly simplifies the number of pairwise covariances that we'll need to estimate.
这样可以大大减少需要估算的协方差的数量
So, now that we have models that describe the individual variances of the two stocks,
我们已经知道两支股票的单独方差模型
what is the pairwise covariance of these two stocks?
这两支股票的协方差呢？
To get the covariance of the two stocks,
为了计算两支股票的协方差
we substitute their returns with the factor models of their returns.
我们将它们的收益率替换为收益率因子模型
Now, we have a covariance of two expressions and each expression
现在协方差有两个表达式
is some weighted sum of two factors and it's specific return.
分别是两个因子的加权和及特有收益率
To help keep track of these formulas,
为了理解这些公式
notice that for the first stock,
假设对于第一支股票
factor 1's contribution is labeled with white sugar,
因子 1 的贡献标为白糖
while factor 2's contribution is labeled with plain milk.
因子 2 的贡献标为纯牛奶
Also, for stock 2,
对于第二支股票
factor 1's contribution is brown sugar,
因子 1 的贡献标为红糖
while factor 2's contribution is chocolate milk.
因子 2 的贡献标为巧克力奶
Our next step is to apply the pairwise covariance operator on each pair of terms.
下一步是将成对协方差运算符应用到成对的每项上
We see that each stock is the sum of three terms.
每支股票包含三项
This would end up with three times three or nine covariances.
所以有 3x3 = 9 个协方差
You can pause the video for a bit to study this.
你可以暂停视频 仔细研究下这部分
By definition, the specific returns are uncorrelated with the factors.
根据定义 特有收益率与因子无关
So, the five pairwise covariances that include the specific returns will become zero.
所以这五对包含特有收益率的协方差将为零
In other words, wherever we see a covariance that contains pecan or chocolate chips,
也就是说 只要协方差包含胡桃或巧克力碎
we'll assume the covariance is zero.
我们就认为协方差为零
The remaining four covariance pairs that include only factors may still be non-zero.
剩下的四对协方差只包含因子 可能不为零
So, we'll keep these.
所以保留下来
These are the four pairwase covariances written out.
这些就是四对协方差
For example, here's the covariance between the contribution of factor 1 to stock 1,
例如 这是因子 1 对股票 1 的贡献
and the contribution of factor 1 to stock 2.
与因子 1 对股票 2 的贡献之间的协方差
The images here are to help you keep track of the notation.
这些图片可以帮助你明白公式中各项的含义
You can see the four pairs of covariances among the white sugar,
这四对协方差表示了
brown sugar, plain milk, and chocolate milk.
白糖 红糖 纯牛奶和巧克力奶之间的协方差